Lee, Jeonghoon

Software Developer

(514) 992-1279 | hoon22.lee@gmail.com | Montreal, Quebec

Profile

A Software developer with 10+ years of experience in software application design and development. Having a strong communication skill, attention to details, and the ability to complete projects in a fast-paced environment.

Skills & Abilities

Programming Languages	Development Tools	Databases and Others
Java /Java Spring	Git / GitHub	HTML5 / CSS3 / Bootstrap
JavaScript / Node.js / React	Visual Studio / VC Code	Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL
C#/ASP.Net, Visual C++	IntelliJ, NetBeans, Eclipse	Google Firebase, Mongo DB
Python		

Language Skills

English: Advanced, French: Intermediate, Korean: Native

Education

	Vanier College, Montreal, A.E.C	01/2021 ~ 05/2021
Web and Database Programming, Continuing Education Attestation Scholar Award		
	John Abbott College, Sainte-Anne-de-Bellevue	10/2018 ~ 09/2020
	Internet Programming and Development	
	Kyungpook National University, South Korea, Master of Science *	03/1995 ~ 02/1997
	Kyungpook National University, South Korea, Bachelor of Science *	03/1991 ~ 02/1995

^{*} Computer Science Major, Canadian equivalency credential was evaluated by WES(World Education Service)

Professional Experience

Freelance Software Developer, South Korea

08/2010 ~ 12/2013

- Design and Develop applications that monitor and control remote devices such as cameras,
 sensors, and motors in Microsoft Windows Environment
- Test and update existing system, and improve system performance
- Visual C++, Win32/MFC library, Visual Basic, MS SQL Server, TCP/UDP, Serial Communication

Professional Experience (Conti.)

Acetel, South Korea 05/2006 ~ 08/2009

Senior Developer / Software team

- Assign, coordinate, and review team members' works and codes
- Design, implement, and test software products
- Led the software team to develop the company's first commercial product, H.264 Professional IRD (Integrated Receiver/Decoder) System
- Visual C++, Win32/MFC library, Linux, MS SQL Server, Multicasting

Gunjarm Digital, South Korea

05/2000 ~ 04/2006

Senior Researcher-Engineer / R&D department

- Design, develop, and maintain MPEG-2 digital broadcasting systems such as encoders, decoders, and transmitters
- Develop and support SDKs of the PCI-type encoding boards in MS Windows environment
- Visual C++, Win32/MFC library, Embedded XP, UDP/RTP, Multicasting

Nongshim Data System (NDS), South Korea

02/1997 ~ 04/2000

Junior Researcher-Engineer / R&D department

- Implement and test the existing groupware system
- Participate in the development of a new webmail and document management system using MS
 Exchange Server
- Visual Basic, Java, JavaScript, CGI, MS Exchange Server / HP OpenMail

Micanan Systems, Dorval

06/2014 ~ 06/2018

Electromechanical Assembler

- Assembly, install, and test according to the drawings and specifications